{
    "id": "8eb3017dc2b249e490736e7af633daba",
    "title": "Intermediate Level Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He would have drowned if the rescuers ………………………….. in time.",
            "description": "In the third conditional we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "didn't arrive",
                "haven't arrived",
                "hadn't arrived"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "36ff30cac7e84b379e9e51e1e29f9496"
        },
        {
            "question": "Would you mind my ………………………. the window?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "open",
                "opening",
                "opened"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6c6e733b8e704c6f9763c0c2945cbb03"
        },
        {
            "question": "Take anything you …………………………",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "want",
                "wanted",
                "will want"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "bfc4894c389640b29ff018247ec8cf45"
        },
        {
            "question": "I knew that she ……………………… support me.",
            "description": "Would is the past tense of will. ",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "shall"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a5c5ea11a1ff410ab5f918ebbdf8bafa"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………. I ran, I could not catch up with him.",
            "description": "Fronted adjectives/adverbs are possible in a structure with as or though.",
            "answers": [
                "Though fast",
                "Fast though",
                "Fast as"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "27dce181596648a69774f9db074e5337"
        },
        {
            "question": "The party was great ……………………..",
            "description": "Fun usually goes after is.",
            "answers": [
                "fun",
                "funny"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e2acfe81822449fc8fdef1d87d462452"
        },
        {
            "question": "Only after her death …………………….. able to appreciate what she did for me.",
            "description": "Inversion is used when a sentence starts with only or hardly or seldom.",
            "answers": [
                "I was",
                "was I"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "71eeb11791f0411f93942f8c4ed80e2d"
        },
        {
            "question": "Hardly …………………… I sat down to rest when the doorbell rang.",
            "description": "It should be hardly did I sit down or hardly had I sat down.",
            "answers": [
                "did",
                "had",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f7a6a3f71fd94f65bd01463a8594a51c"
        },
        {
            "question": "‘I don’t like oysters.’ ‘……………….. do I.’",
            "description": "After a negative remark, we can add another negative remark with 'neither + auxiliary + noun/pronoun.'",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "either",
                "neither"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "6a89aec5e00348d7973988010b42b948"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. we heard the gunshots, we rushed upstairs.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "No sooner",
                "As soon as",
                "Hardly had"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6e70fa3a2c8d43efae66a6345fe70994"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where ……………………. all this while?",
            "description": "The present perfect indicates time up to now. ",
            "answers": [
                "were you",
                "have you been",
                "are you"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "7d9a947056f84c779cd2fe10ec852d81"
        },
        {
            "question": "It was the last message I ……………………….. from him.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "get",
                "got",
                "have got"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "42977bac41a24e6bb67f3fa330b5183b"
        }
    ]
}